<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog</title><link>https://wsdookadr.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wsdookadr.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Non-standard solutions to some technical problems</title><link>https://wsdookadr.github.io/posts/p2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wsdookadr.github.io/posts/p2/</guid><description>Intro When I’m interviewing for contracts or for jobs, many times I get asked what are the hardest problems I’ve had to deal with. I’ll write below some of these problems as I remember them now.
Double-counting Some years ago, I was a consultant for a job in an analytics team. I was tasked with finding a bug in code that was counting the views of a top-10 Alexa website with hundreds of millions of views every month.</description></item><item><title>Setting up the new blog</title><link>https://wsdookadr.github.io/posts/p1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wsdookadr.github.io/posts/p1/</guid><description>Previous setup Previously I was writing a blog using the following: Emacs + Org-Mode + Jekyll. Here is a short assessment of that setup:
The pros:
Emacs tries to pack as much functionality as possible without the need for external dependencies
Org-Mode allows you to have runnable code blocks and include the results of said code blocks inside the rendered version of the documents. The active document concept is really nice (but nowadays that’s also achievable with Jupyter)</description></item><item><title>Services</title><link>https://wsdookadr.github.io/services/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wsdookadr.github.io/services/</guid><description>Beginning with 2016, S.C. MAGNA SOFTWARE S.R.L offers services to clients world-wide, provides reliable software solutions to add value to the customers products and projects. Some of the key points in the delivered solutions are optimizing and improving the client’s infrastructure, making pertinent and value-adding suggestions on the technical side, crafting tools and algorithms that aid in solving data problems and increase visibility into existing systems.
For more details, see the details below.</description></item></channel></rss>